The reason why it's there
is I will protect you
Don't worry, let's go ahead
The moon will come to the moon
The moon will come to the
moon Let's look at the moon
Fire! Emergency!
Everybody wake up! Damn them!
Those pirates started this, didn't they?
We need to do something quick!
There's still a lot of people left inside!
Iceberg might be trapped!
Let's make sure he made it out!
Right! Come on!
The rest of you!
Put out that fire! Go! Go!
It appears the fire is
beginning to spread.
Leopard, human, whatever the hell you are,
you're not going to lay one
finger on Iceberg, you hear me?
No, he's a carnivore Snow type.
They're the most brutal of them all.
Indeed.
Logia-types,
Zoan-types, Paramethia-types, each one
extremely powerful in their own unique way.
The ability to enhance
one's own personal strength
happens to be the
specialty of the Zoan-type.
In other words, the more we
train, the stronger we get.
Which makes the Zoan-type the most lethal
when it comes to attacks at close range.
Iceberg! Go! Move it!
Luchi, the workmen are making their
way up the stairs. Don't worry.
They'll never make it this far.
Tempest kick!
Go back!
The ceiling's collapsing!
Nami, Dada!
Chopper!
What are you doing?
No matter what, I'm
getting you out of here.
There's no way your wounds are far too...
I'm afraid we can't let you do that.
And I'm afraid, you're gonna have to.
Damn you!
Why did it have to be you guys?
No, I can't believe you!
How could you do this?
You tricked me!
I thought you were my friends!
Then you are mistaken.
Talking pigeon jerk!
Luffy, what are you?
Finger pistol.
Luffy!
Have a nice flight.
Noooooooo!
Kalifa!
Damn you!
Iron body!
Now it's your turn.
Did everyone make it out?
It's taken the building.
We can't go back inside.
Have each team check to
see if anyone's missing.
Hey, have you heard
anything about Iceberg?
Is he safe?
Don't tell me.
He's not stuck in there, is he?
Of course not.
The foremen are with him!
There's no way they left him behind!
Search the area!
I'm sure he's here somewhere!
Hey, wait.
That woman's one of the Straw Hats.
I'm sure of it.
Did she jump out from one of the windows?
She probably got trapped by the fire and
didn't have any other choice in the matter.
Well, what should we do with her?
These damn pirates have
done a terrible thing here.
Let's make her tell us where
the rest of her crew is.
We'll hunt them down and
turn them over to the Navy.
The testimony of a pirate
won't hold up as evidence.
This case will remain a mystery.
Iceberg, no matter how great of
a shipbuilding engineer you are,
no matter how great a mayor,
a mere individual citizen shouldn't
oppose the world government.
Let's go we need to find tom's
other apprentice Franky or
rather cutty flab and take
those blueprints away from him?
Granny! Granny!
There's a huge fire!
It's Galilaw's main office.
Such a terrible thing to do.
What do you mean, Granny?
Did someone start the fire on purpose?
Well, I can't really say for sure.
But usually, when I get a bad
feeling, it turns out to be right.
I sure hope that Iceberg is doing okay.
Seriously, all this is happening over
that thing, it shouldn't even exist.
You're sure of it, you saw Franky
wandering into your bar earlier?
Yeah, I spoke with him, but he
took off to go look for Straw Hat.
I see.
Seems like he doesn't stay
in one place for very long.
Wow.
Some people just have the
worst sense of timing.
Look, there.
Listen up, Straw Hat!
We've got Long Nose! That's right!
We totally have him!
If you don't want him to sing
in the key of C! You idiot!
How many times do I have to tell you it's
if you don't want him
to sink into the sea?
Break some iced tea!
The sea! Are you deaf?
What kind of threat is that?
It doesn't make any sense.
Whatever!
All that matters is getting
the message to Straw Hat!
Giving him that stupid
message won't do any good.
And, bro, Franky will
end up kicking your butt.
If you don't want him sunk
to the bottom of the sea,
go to the warehouse under the
bridge with the guards, Franky!
Like that!
If he gets the message and he does come,
bro's gonna beat the
living crap out of him.
Who did you say is waiting for whom?
And where is this certain someone waiting?
Huh?
Who the hell are you?
We're kind of busy right now.
Get lost!
If you want to live, you'll answer my
question in the next three seconds.
Huh?
Is that some kind of joke, you nutjob?
Do you even have the slightest clue
as to what family we're a part of?
What did you mean by the
warehouse under the bridge?
Is that the place where Franky is?
Whatever business you have with Franky?
He's gonna have to go
through us first, right guys?
Why in the world are the three
of you crying about it? What?
We're not crying, you idiot!
I was just thinking
about everything you've
been through to protect
that ship all alone,
and it touched my heart!
We're not crying!
None of us are crying!
What the heck is wrong with these nitwits?
Anyway, you get the gist of it, right?
We're no longer friends!
The Straw Hats are part of my past now!
It's so sad!
So sad that I'll have to sing about it!
This song is called Severed
Friendship, North Wind Child!
Yeah! Sing it, bro!
Hey!
Are you making fun of me?!
Is the tea ready yet?
I'm dying of thirst over here. Almost.
We'll bring it over in just a moment.
Wow.
That crying wore me out.
Not that I really cried.
Here you go, bro.
Now be careful, it's really hot.
Thank you so much.
Okay, I understand what's what, brother.
She just got through telling you that!
Calm down!
Sorry about that, bro. You okay?
Why don't you take a break
and have some tea as well?
I can't blame you.
You must be holding quite
the grudge against us.
You know, since we stole your
200 million berries and all.
Especially because it led to such
a big fight with your captain.
Whatever.
What happens, happens.
No sense holding a grudge about it.
Taking the high road.
Oh, manly.
About that money.
I spent all of it!
I'm gonna knock you flat.
Now, now, don't get so worked up,
especially after you showed me?
how dignified and forgiving you are.
Come on, brother.
Can't we just let bygones
be bygones? I mean,
I haven't flipped out on you for destroying
my home and demolition factory, have I?
And on top of that, you guys
annihilated my subordinates.
You bastards, how dare you all kill you?
Easy, bro, you gotta control that anger.
Arrgh!
Yep,
a lot has happened these past few days,
but I do think we're better
off putting it all behind us.
So what do you say we just put the
axe in the ground and call it a day?
I think you mean bury the hatchet.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure it's
bury the hatchet, bro.
So what's next?
What will you do now
that you're on your own?
It doesn't seem like
you have anywhere to go.
Tell you what why don't
you let me take care of you
join the Franky family
You seem like a good man,
and I can always get it.
I have no plans to
become a ship dismantler
Even though I'm no longer a Straw Hat.
I am still a pirate got it
You've moved me to song.
This is the pirate code
Don't sing it and I still
think you're making fun of me
Look, I'm just concerned, that's all.
I'm thinking about your future.
My future is none of your business.
Besides,
there are other things you should
be concerned with right now,
like that huge storm headed this way.
True, but we're safe here.
Aqua Laguna can be pretty devastating.
When it hits, we all
have to pull together.
Starting now until late into the night,
houses will be submerged
up to the second floor.
If you're stuck in the back
streets or capes during that time,
You don't stand a chance,
but this area is safe.
Your ship will be safe, too,
if you want to keep it here.
Oh, thank you very much.
I really appreciate it.
Stop acting like we're strangers, moron!
I imagine it must be
tough having to deal with
this storm and the chaos
it causes every year.
Nah, it's not so bad.
We've all gotten used to
the annual evacuation.
The real problem is the water level.
It increases little by
little every single year.
The back streets you see all
through Water 7 are built on the
rooftops of an old town that
existed several hundred years ago.
It's said that the shipbuilding
island and the back
streets used to be part
of the same piece of land.
But now, so much of it
has sunk under the sea.
That's why they call it a floating city.
All the sidewalks became
canals and waterways.
If you want to be more precise about it,
technically, rather than saying
the water level is increasing,
the foundation of the
island is actually sinking.
If it keeps up, the city will
become harder and harder to live in.
I see.
Even this beautiful city of water has
its share of hardships, too, doesn't it?
Hmm. But still,
if push comes to shove,
you can just take the Sea Train
and go live somewhere else, right?
You can say that now.
But not always.
It's only been around for ten years.
Before that time, you
were totally out of luck.
Getting across the ocean without it's
no easy task, even if you have a boat.
Huh?
This island is isolated.
There was never much
traffic to or from it.
The people who lived here carried
with them the looming fear that
someday this entire city and everything
around it would sink into the sea.
They became hopeless.
The one thing that finally
took away that fear
was the Sea Train the
puffing tom now anyone
at any time can travel
across the sea without
a Log Pose this was a
huge step for the island
And we owe everything to one man,
a brilliant shipwright named Tom,
who created that C-train.
He saved us all, and he
gave this island new life.
Bro!
Help me!
I'll say hello to your bro for
you when we pay him a visit.
We now know the location.
Let's go.
Hey, got a question for you, brother.
I'll just get right to the point.
What are you going to do
after you fix that ship?
Well, let's see.
First, we'll go on a
few adventures together,
and eventually I'll sail her back
to our home in the East Blue!
I know we didn't sail around
the world or anything,
but the Mary and I made it
all the way to the Grand Line!
I'd call that a successful voyage that
will end with a triumphant return!
So with our heads held high...
Nope, sorry.
Not gonna happen.
You can't go all the way
back to the East Blue.
It's too far away.
What do you mean?
I took a close look at your ship when
we were bringing it up here earlier.
Got to see her from every angle.
That ship is at the end of her life.
Galilaw's assessment was correct.
As an expert in the demolition
business, I suggest you dismantle her.
What?
That's ridiculous.
I'll even help you do the job.
Like I said, I'm an expert.
Are you crazy?
What in the hell are you
talking about, you jerk?
Hold on!
Don't come any closer! Stop!
I need it!
Take it easy.
I'm simply offering to help
demolish this ship, that's all.
Stop screwing around!
I'm not going to let you
anywhere near her, understand?
Get lost!
The Mary is my ship!
You're wrong. Listen.
That old girl's no longer a ship.
Huh?
What'd you say? Earlier,
I asked you a question about what you
planned on doing once you fixed that ship.
Now,
if you had said that you
were going to cast away
your life to the sea and
go down along with her,
then,
well, I wouldn't have had
anything to say about it.
No questions.
But,
since you just told me
that you plan on going
all the way back to
the East Blue with her,
well, now I have to stop you, brother.
Yes.
That ship is at her end.
She won't even make it to the next island.
Listen, a ship is born with one promise.
to carry you across the sea
from one shore to another.
That's her sole purpose.
The reason for her existence.
Which means,
when the time comes that a ship can
no longer carry you across the sea...
Hey, stop!
No!
Then that promise has been broken,
and she's no longer a ship!
Bro!
No! Stop it!
You bastard!
Keep away from the Mary's!
Oh, son of a bitch!
If you don't understand!
Then, take a look with your own damn eyes!
SIGHS
Oh, my God.
Oh, no.
Sorry, Mary.
Don't worry.
I'll fix you up right away.
Every time.
As many times as you need.
No matter what.
I'll always take care of you.
Always.
Hey, enough already, Long Nose.
You saw the bottom of the ship, right?
The keel is broken right down the middle.
The outer panels are slipping
off and the frame is shot.
With a hull like that, the
first wave would rip her apart.
And you think that a complete amateur
like you can just grab a hammer and...
You shut your damn mouth!
I don't want to hear
another word out of you!
If you so much as breathe, I'll
kick your teeth and you'll hear me!
Beside.
Huh?
What did you say?
In my heart, I knew it all along.
I knew the truth!
I knew that the Mary was
at the end of our lives!
Deep down, I knew it.
When I heard the assessment,
I knew that what I saw on that day
back in Skypiea really happened.
At first, I thought I was dreaming
that there was no way it could be real.
On one foggy night,
in a forest lit with
nothing but moonlight,
I heard the hammering
strikes of a wooden mallet.
It sounded like it was coming from the
direction of the ship, but at the time!
there shouldn't have
been anybody on board.
I crept closer.
It confirmed the sound was
indeed coming from the Mary.
The fog was thick, but I'm
sure I saw someone there?
striking away with a wooden mallet.
I couldn't figure out who it was.
Whoa, check it out!
On the morning of the next day,
We awoke to find that the ship
had been haphazardly repaired.
Even the broken mast was back
where it had always been.
But there was something even more
peculiar that was bugging me.
Whoever fixed the Mary
knew how she used to look.
Despite all the
modifications we made to her,
this mysterious person had brought
her back to her original shape.
She was still in rough condition, but she
was the same old Mary she had been before.
The whole situation remained a mystery,
but for some reason these
words lingered in my heart.
I don't know if it's something
I actually heard someone say,
or maybe just something I imagined.
Don't worry.
I'll carry everyone for
a little bit longer.
I know it sounds ridiculous, but I...
I think it was the
incarnation of the Mary,
and she spoke to me.
She probably already knew
that she was at her limits,
and so she appeared in
that form to tell us.
She wanted to reassure us
that it'd be all right.
That's what I thought of when I
heard her assessment from Galley-La.
You think I'm completely
out of my mind, don't you?
I don't care, you don't
have to believe me.
What is it, bro?
Whether I believe it or not,
you said that whoever it was you saw?
looked like someone holding
a wooden mallet, right?
That's right.
Does it mean something?
Yeah, it sure does.
It means that you saw a Klebautermon.
Kle-Kleba-what?
A Klebautermon.
It's an old legend that's passed
down from sailor to sailor.
It's a very particular type of ferry.
It only dwells on ships
treated with great care.
You could say it's the ship's spirit.
It's said that it carries a wooden mallet
in its hand and wears a sailor's raincoat.
At times when the vessel is in danger,
it'll run around the ship and
find some way to warn everyone.
I've heard that they help
sailors in other ways, too.
But to be honest,
this is the first time I've ever heard
someone say outright that they've seen one.
The more care a ship receives, the more
they grow to appreciate the sailors.
This ship must have been determined to
make sure you made it to the next shore,
no matter what.
Just think about it.
This ship had a caring crew
that was so special to her,
she even appeared in
human form to reassure
them that everything
was going to be alright.
I bet you she's been very happy.
Mary.
I see.
So, it was you.
You were the one who made those repairs
and spoke to me back then, weren't you?
Mary.
As amazing as that is, I'm still confused.
Tell me,
why would you have a big fight with your
crew when you knew the ship was done for?
It's not that simple.
I'll never understand
why men are so stupid!
You're such idiots!
Sounds like someone's at the door.
Someone who else would it be?
But zombie and the others!
Why would they take the long way
and come in from the seaside?
Yeah, that's odd.
They normally come in
through the upper entrance.
Maybe they had to because they
were able to capture Straw Hat.
That's right, I forgot.
I kidnapped you to use your
bait to lure out your crew.
They won't come!
I'm no longer part of that crew, remember?
That plan won't work
Why are they ringing the bell
when they can just come in?
How annoying?
Okay, okay, hold on, I'm coming!
Enough already, we hear you!
Hold on a second!
All right, brother, listen, I think what
you should do is go back to your friends.
It's impossible to do that now.
I challenge the captain
to a duel for starters!
And then there's the matter of the
ship that hasn't been settled yet?
What do you mean hasn't been settled?
If your ship can't sail anymore,
then it can't sail anymore
That's the end of it, right?
Just leave her here with me, okay?
I'll take care of her in a
way that you'd approve of.
Problem solved.
I wasn't thinking about
what I was doing earlier.
I tried to dismantle the ship without
considering what would be best for you.
It'll be different this time.
This is my problem!
Stay out of it, okay?
Hey, I'm just trying to help
you - Is that you, zombie?
Show some gratitude, will ya?
Gratitude?
You've got to be kidding me!
Don't you understand this situation?
As hard as it is for you,
it's worse on the ship.
She loves you guys so much that
she appeared to you in human form.
If she sinks to the bottom of the
sea while you're still on board,
then all of that will
have been for nothing.
Get it?
If that happens, her final moments
will be filled with regret.
She won't be able to die in peace.
Is that what you'd do?
After everything you'd
been through together,
you'd leave one of your friends
behind to die on their own?
Just throw them aside like trash?
That's not the same thing at all.
This is completely different.
It is the same thing, and
that's exactly what's going on!
Ugh, you just don't get it!
Mozu!
Kiwi!
I apologize for the interruption.
It's just those two ladies weren't being
very accommodating about letting us in.
What the hell are you
bastards doing down here?
Iron body.
Hey, what's the big idea?
What gives, Belt?
You got some kind of problem with me?
We're trying to pull a reverse move, huh?
You dumbass, you should
know better than that.
No one pushes me around.
You should be pouring
me a drink, remember?
What, you forget you're just a bartender?
And what's up with that outfit anyway?
What the hell are you up to?
Not yet.
Whoa, are you okay?
Killing him now would put
our mission in jeopardy.
We need him alive.
Hey, what's going on here?
I mean, what did you do to piss
off these shipyard guys so bad?
The freak with the bird?
How'd he get a hit like that on me?
And what's the deal?
Why are you guys coming
in on my turf with a chip
on your shoulders acting
like you own the place?
And hitting girls?
That's so not cool!
Kiwi and Mozu were like my little sisters!
You know, how'd you freaks
even find us here anyway?
This is my ultra top secret base!
How we found you is irrelevant,
as we are here right now.
But know this we came to this town
assigned to a covert operation
with special agents spies
working for the world government.
I Assume even you would know why
we came here and what we're after?
Franky we know the secret
that you're keeping.
Cutty Flam
The rumor was that Tom's apprentice
perished about eight years ago.
But you're still alive.
That's some pretty amazing detective work
i'm real impressed but i'm starting to
get a sour feeling down in my gut where
is he where the hell is iceberg he's dead.
It's too late to feign innocence
we already know everything.
It's only a matter of time
before the government targets me.
I want you to take these and
leave this island, Franky.
Tom entrusted them to Iceberg,
and Iceberg entrusted them to you.
Hey, boys, come here.
It's about time I let you
in on something important.
It's been a long game,
but now we're a checkmate.
See, I know you have the
plans for the ancient weapon.
Hand over Pluton's blueprints, Kaido Flam.
Flam, huh?
That's kind of a funny name.
How about we just call you Franky instead?
Whatever.
Are you listening?
Hand them over this instant.
Oh, did you just say hand?
What the hell did he just do?
It was so fast I couldn't see
what happened. Hey! Are you okay?
Oh, my.
You found a room.
What do you suppose is this
filthy place's purpose?
Those are drafting tables.
Yes, where blueprints are
made, and perhaps hidden.
Find them.
Look here, nameplates, Kaido Flam,
Iceberg, Tom, the Shipwright.
This picture.
Keep your paws off of that.
You're poking your noses into
my personal space, my memories.
This is the place where I grew up.
What used to house the shipbuilding
company, Tom's Workers?